[Music]
foreign
by which they mean all kinds of beans
chickpeas split peas and lentils are an
excellent source of many essential
nutrients vitamins minerals fibers
antioxidants and not just an excellent
source perhaps the single cheapest
source in terms of nutrition density per
Penny the four that really pull out from
the pack are pinto beans lentils black
beans and kidney beans
and all that nutritional quality may
have beneficial effects on excess body
weight insulin resistance high
cholesterol inflammation and oxidative
stress all major cardiovascular risk
factors so do men and women who eat more
beans tend to have less heart disease
yes suggesting that increasing legume
intake may be an important part of a
dietary approach to the primary
prevention of coronary heart disease in
the general population meaning
prevention of heart disease in the first
place
but yeah maybe those eating more bean
burritos or just eating less beef
burritos they took that into account
controlling for meat intake fruits and
vegetables and smoking and exercise and
still the bean eaters appeared to be
protected note the highest category here
was eating legumes four more times a
week in my daily dozen I recommend
people eat legumes three times a day in
Costa Rica they were able to find enough
people eating beans every day and so
even after controlling from any of the
same things like intake of saturated fat
and cholesterol one bean surfing a day
was associated with a 38 reduction in
the risk of heart attack
yep but do you actually get to live
longer too yes apparently so in eight
percent lower all-cause mortality again
after adjusting for other dietary
factors you can't control for everything
though I mean you can't really prove
cause and effect until you put it to the
test randomize controlled Interventional
trials have found that dietary Bean
intake does significantly reduce bad
cholesterol levels dating back a half
century to 1962 measure cholesterol
levels at Baseline and then add beans to
their diet and then remove beans from
their diet
and look beans have low glycemic index
and saturated fat content and or high in
fiber potassium plant protein Each of
which independently converts blood
pressure lowering effects but whether
there's sufficient evidence to emphasize
beans alone to lower blood pressure is
unclear therefore what we need is a
systematic review and meta-analysis of
controlled feeding trials and here it is
and what they found is that beings do
indeed lower blood pressure no matter
where you start out
okay so beans may be able to prevent
artery disease but what about reversing
it
can the daily conception of beans other
than soy reverse vascular impairment due
to peripheral artery disease and
peripheral artery disease results from a
decrease in blood flow to the legs due
to a buildup of atherosclerotic plaque
higher up yeah soybeans may help but
what about other beans
so they had 26 individuals with
peripheral artery disease consume one
serving a day of a combination of beans
split peas lentils and chickpeas for
eight weeks basically how you diagnose
and follow the disease is with the ankle
brachial index which is just the ratio
of blood pressure at your ankle compared
to your arm once it dips below 0.9 that
means you must have some kind of clogs
and blood flow to your lower body
but eat some beans and you may get a
significant increase enough to push four
of 26 participants up into the normal
range after just eight weeks eating some
beans
now there was no control group but you
know people tend to get worse not better
the researchers conclude a legume Rich
diet can elicit major improvements in
arterial function
before
foreign